Dr. Chanda Bloch

Strategic • Relator • Visionary • Individualization • Learner

chanda.bloch@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Educational leader with 23 years of public education experience and a passion for maximizing teams of stakeholders to advance an organization's vision and values.

Core Competencies

- Coaching Campus Administration on How to Create Strong School Culture and Campus-Wide Systems
- School Redesign
- Creating Innovative, Strategic Plans for District & Campus Programs
- Professional Learning & Thoughtful Use of Instructional Technology
- Literacy Instructional Best Practices, Management, & Design
- Building Relationships in Service

Key Achievements & Strengths

District Leadership: Created and maintained Academic Budgets and collaborated on strategic staffing and recruitment plans across multiple districts.

Strategic Planning: Co-led a 5-year Strategic Planning process and helped pass a \$90 million bond for school construction and renovation.

Program Development: Helped launch P-Tech Program and Early College High School initiatives to expand student opportunities.

School Improvement: Took over an "F" rated campus and moved it to a letter grade "C" in one academic year.

Professional Learning: Created and delivered Principal and Assistant Principal Professional Learning Communities, meetings, and trainings.

Collaboration: Worked with Texas State University to design Teacher Residency Programs and Dual Credit opportunities.

Certifications

- Superintendency Certification Baylor University
- Principal Certification Program Texas A&M Kingsville

Professional Experience

Superintendent of Schools

2024-Present Hamlin Collegiate ISD

- Created and maintained Academic Budget and helped to oversee each campus budget in the district.
- Collaborated with Chief of Operations and Chief of Finance to design the new Elementary school and remodel current schools.
- Collaborated with Human Resource department to create strategic staffing and recruitment plans for hard to fill vacancies.
- Worked with Senior Leadership to create district-wide mission and vision aligned with student success and college and career readiness.
- Created and delivered all Principal and Assistant Principal Professional Learning Communities, meetings, and trainings.

Assistant Superintendent of School Leadership and Student Support 2022-2024

San Marcos CISD

- Led planning, development, implementation, and feedback loops of K-12 professional learning including PLCs, Effective Feedback, Instructional Playbook, Restorative Practices, and AVID.
- Collaborated with Texas State University to create Dual Credit and Early College High School opportunities.
- Co-wrote district policy and best practices for K-12 grading guidelines.
- Co-led 5-year Strategic Planning process and helped pass a \$90 million bond for new construction and renovations.
- Designed Teacher Residency Program placing over 50 teacher residents each academic vear.
- Created and maintained Academic Budget and helped oversee campus budgets.
- Collaborated with Senior Leadership to reduce district deficit by reviewing staffing allocations and resources.
- Created and delivered Principal and Assistant Principal Professional Learning Communities, meetings, and trainings.

Director of Secondary Schools and Instruction

2020-2022

Seguin ISD

- Collaborated with middle and high school administration, district leadership, teachers, students, and families to guide equitable, innovative, standards-driven teaching and learning.
- Led planning, development, implementation, and feedback loops of K-12 professional learning; supervised District Curriculum Content Coordinators and Campus Academic Deans.
- Collaborated with Transcend and Texas Education Agency to create a middle school redesign.
- Implemented and supported new High Qualified Instructional Materials Curriculum in grades 6-12.
- Created and supported district-wide observation/feedback cycle to support teachers.
- Trained campus administration in Crucial Conversations, Data Driven Instruction, and PLCs.

High School Principal

2018-2020

Seguin ISD

- Led and supervised teams of teachers and support staff for smooth day-to-day operations and positive learning environment.
- Developed and implemented innovative curriculum and instructional strategies improving academic performance and engagement.
- Collaborated with parents, teachers, and community members to establish partnerships and improve involvement.
- Helped launch P-Tech Program allowing students to earn Associate Degree and Pharmacy Certification.
- Created campus-wide systems in academics, safety, and discipline to maximize results.
- Oversaw Early College High School and Advanced Academics Programs.
- Created Virtual Learning plan for all Secondary campuses during the pandemic.
- Accountability Rating 2020-21: B

Elementary Principal

2013-2018

Seguin ISD

- Led campus through change from Early Exit Bilingual Program to Dual Language Program.
- Led and supervised teams ensuring smooth operations and positive learning environment.
- Developed and implemented innovative curriculum and instructional strategies improving academic performance and engagement.
- Collaborated with parents, teachers, and community members to establish partnerships and improve involvement.

- Oversaw implementation of school-wide initiatives including social-emotional learning and professional development workshops.
- Took over an "F" rated campus and moved it to a letter grade "C" in one academic year.
- Accountability Rating 2016-17: B and 2017-18: B

Assistant Principal

2010-2012

La Vernia ISD

- Served as 504 Campus Coordinator, MTSS Coordinator, Restorative Discipline, and Campus Testing Coordinator.
- Created and prepared campus community, team leader, and faculty meetings and professional development agendas.
- Supported PLCs and student growth in Tier 1 best practices prior to referral to Tiers 2 & 3.
- Trained and supported campus culture and practices with Capturing Kids Hearts and restorative practices.
- Accountability Rating 2012-13: A

Education

- Educational Leadership Ed.D., Baylor University 2021 (Superintendency Certification)
- M.Ed. Educational Leadership, Texas A&M Kingsville 2007 (Principal Certification Program)
- Bachelor of Science in Communication Studies and English, Texas State University 2003 (Focus: Secondary Education in Debate, Speech and English)